(
"ai_sub_version": "3.5.2",
"generated_at": "2026-08-20T09:00:49.520980",
"lyrics_prompt_version": 9,
"subtitles_prompt_version": 18,
"complete": true,
"max_retries_exceeded": false,
"any_pending": false,
"settings": (
"ai": (
"model": null,
"model_subtitles": "google-gla:gemini-3.5-flash-lite",
"model_lyrics": "google-gla:gemini-3.5-flash-lite",
"rpm": 4,
"tpm": 250000,
"google": (
"file_cache_ttl": 10,
"use_files_api": true,
"max_storage_gb": 18.0
),
"search": (
"qps": 0.3,
"max_length": 4096,
"web_search_tool": "langsearch",
"timeout": 60.0,
"retries": 3,
"min_wait_seconds": 1.0,
"max_wait_seconds": 10.0,
"multiplier": 2.0
),
"validation_buffer_ms": 2000,
"verification_gap_seconds": 60,
"gap_verification_retries": 1,
"gap_verification_ignore_start": true,
"gap_verification_ignore_end": true
),
"split": (
"max_seconds": 300,
"re_encode": (
"enabled": false,
"fps": 1.0,
"height": 360,
"bitrate_kb": 35,
"threshold_mb": 20,
"duration_tolerance_ms": 100,
"encoder": null
),
"start_offset_min": 0
"thread": (
"uploads": 4,
"re_encode": 2,
"lyrics": 4,
"subtitles": 4
),
"retry": (
"per_run": 5,
"max_runs": 3,
"multiplier": 2.0,
"min_wait_seconds": 30.0,
"max_wait_seconds": 300
),
"log": (
"level": "info",
"timestamps": true,
"scrub": false,
"progress_bars": true,
"progress_bar_width": 80,
"progress_bar_refresh_seconds": 1.0
)
ラライ、ラライ、ラライ、ララライヨー、ラライ、ラライ
La-la, la-la, la-la-la-la-la-la-la!
ほい、ほい！こっち！こっち！
Here! Over here!
わーーい！見て、見て！
Yay! Look, look!
わあ！いっぱいなんかいろんなのある！
Hey, look at that! There's so much stuff!
なに、なに！めっちゃすごい！
What? Look over there!
チョコバナナ！え、チョコバナナ！
Chocolate bananas!
やだやだやだやだ！
No way, no way, no way, no way!
チョコバナナはだめ！
Wait, chocolate bananas are no good!
なんで？
Why?
いやいや、そのチョコバナナはまずい！
Wait, chocolate bananas are bad news!
え？なんで？なんで？
Why? Because...
なんか急にこの手でびっくりしちゃうから！
You'll suddenly get startled by this hand!
チョコバナナだ！チョコバナナだ！
Right? We should start with chocolate bananas!
チョコバナナ食べよう！チョコバナナ食べよう！
Let's eat chocolate bananas! Eat chocolate bananas!
こっちだよ！
It's over here!
あ、店員さんによう！ねえ、やって店員さん！
Hey, go ask the clerk!
店員さんやって！
Do it, clerk!
ちょっと、髪の毛の玉wrap消えないで！
Hey, Lamy, don't let your hair wrap swing around!
チョコバナナおいくつ必要ですか？
Hey, how many chocolate bananas do we need?
三つでーす！あ、三つきた！
Three! Three!
ラミィがチョコバナナをご所望で！
Lamy wants chocolate bananas!
ピンク！
Pink!
ピンク！ピンク！ピンク！
Pink! Pink! Pink!
じゃんけんで勝てばもう1本なんでしょ？
If we win rock-paper-scissors, is it just one more?
え？そうなの？
Yeah, is that so?
ぽいっ！ぽいっ！
Poi! Poi!
あ、そんなんだと負けるぞ！
Ah, if you do that, you'll lose!
いっ atéまーでやる！いっ atéまーでやる！これ！
We'll do it until we win! Until we win!
もう始まってるよ！
It's starting!
みんな！でかけほりーで！
Everyone, let's go!
なんか、あ、獅白の浴衣が、何それ？本当？どうすればいいの？
Hey, what's up with Shishiro's yukata?
どうすればいいの？
Wait, what's with that hair?
ちょっと待って！この縁日のところ、横にやんよ！お客さんに迷惑じゃん！
Hey, look, at this Ennichi spot, there's no room, customers are annoyed!
あ、ちょっと、ちょっと、じゃんけんぽんってやっちゃうから。
Wait, wait, wait, if you do rock-paper-scissors...
ライオンの足してないから！
Lion's foot isn't there, so...
はい、ということでね、ほらはい、自己紹介しますか！
Alright, then, let's introduce ourselves!
いっくよー！はい、せーの！
Let's go! Let's go!
ホロライブのね、ホロライブ5期生オレンジ担当桃鈴ねねです！
Hololive's 5th Generation, Orange Tan-tan and Moomusume!
ぶんぶんぶんぶーん！
Bun-bun-bum!
はい、ねぽらのぽさん！
Hey, I'm Nenechi!
はい、ねぽらのぽ、おるかおるか？おるよー！
Hey, I'm Nenechi's Po!
ホロライブ5期生おまるぽるかです！
Hololive 5th Generation, Omaru Polka!
いぇーい！
Let's go!
はい、ねぽらのら、がおうかんとゆきはらみです！
Hololive 5th Gen's Ra—Katsugakan—Yukihana Lami!
いぇーい！
Yay!
そして最後は！
And finally!
はい、ねぽらのぼ、ししろぼたんでーす！
Hololive 5th Gen's Bo—Shiro Botan!
いぇーい！
Yay!
ということでね、7月7日開催の！
So, everyone, July 7th is the live event!
ホロライブ！
Hololive 5th Generation Live!
ほい！ホロライブ！
FIFTH GENERATION LIVE "Twinkle 4 You"に向けて！
"Twinkle 4 You"!
はい、ねぽらぼが大集合です！
Yeah, Neporabo is all together!
いぇーい！いぇーい！
Yay! Yay!
ねえ、ねえ、ねえ！
Hey, hey!
わたくし初なんですけれども！
Well, I'm the first, but...
ちょっと、夏を！
Wait, summer!
先取りして今日は浴衣を着てみましたー！
Let's get ahead of summer and wear yukatas today!
いぇーい！いいじゃん、いいじゃん！
Good, good!
いいじゃん、いいじゃん！
That's great!
ちょ、ちょ、ちょ、ちょ！邪魔なんだわ！
Stop it! Stop it! Stop it!
みんな振り回してるんだから！
Everyone is swinging around!
振り回すものじゃないから！
Don't swing around!
なんで、なんで振り回すの、ラミィ！ねえ！
Hey, why are you swinging it, Lamy?
ねえ、ヨーヨーが！
Hey, yo-yo...
なに？
What?
押してください、ちゃんと！
Push it properly!
え、あれここ一番真面目に今写真に写ってるのに、何どこ笑ってんの？
Hey, we're taking a picture here so seriously right now, why are you laughing?
一緒にほら呼んでください先に。
Call it together with us first!
せーの、ねぽらぼです！
Ready, we are NEPOLABO!
ねぇ、何？この丸いものは何なんだろね？
Hey, what is this round thing?
こんなものまで持っちゃってさー。
Holding something like this.
これ何、これ何？何これ？これ何？
What is this, what is this? What's this? What's this?
これ持ってるの？痛い。落ち着いて。落ち着いてよ、ぼるが真面目にやっ、呼んでください。
You're holding it? Ow, calm down. Calm down, Boru, do it properly. Call it.
これ何？これ何？ねえみんな、気になる、気になるところですけど
What is this? What is this? Hey everyone, we're curious about this, but
気になるところですけど、ちょっとやめて。
we're curious, so stop it.
これね、ちゃんと、あとでね、ちゃーんと説明するんで！
We'll explain all of this properly later!
はい、あの配信をね、最後まで見てください。邪魔なんで本当にやめてください。
Yes, please watch the stream until the end. You're in the way, please stop.
多分45分後ぐらいに説明あると思うわ。やめて！やめて！それまでね、にちゃく見といてください皆さん。
There'll probably be an explanation in about 45 minutes. Stop! Stop! Until then, watch the second place, everyone.
またあとで会おう！
Let's meet again later!
ねえねえ、浴衣の、のびちゃん！やめましょう！はい！という事で！
Hey hey, Nene-chan's yukata is stretching! Stop it! Yes! So!
え？え？え？大丈夫？
Eh? Eh? Eh? Are you okay?
はい！いや、先生！
Yes! No, Sensei!
はい！何ですか？ねねさん！え、今日は一体何をするんですか？
Yes! What is it, Nene-san? Eh, what are we doing today?
はい、よくぞ聞いてくれました！これで進めることができます！
Yes, thank you for asking! With this, we can proceed!
はい、皆さん、えっと七夕が開催される7月7日、何の日ですか？
Yes, everyone, um, July 7th when Tanabata is held, what day is it?
たなばたー！たなばたー！はい！よくできました！七夕です！
Tanabata! Tanabata! Yes! Well done! It's Tanabata!
今日はね、七夕にかけて事前に、え、皆さんの悩みを募集いたしました！
Today, tied with Tanabata, we solicited everyone's troubles in advance!
ちょっと待って待って、全然できないからって動かないでください。私たちが何かやるんですか？
Wait wait, don't move just because you can't do it at all. Are we going to do something?
そう、そうです、そうです！はい、はい、はい。
Yes, that's right! Yes, yes, yes.
あの聞いてくださいよ。今日の企画は
Please listen. Today's project is
いいですか？進めますよ？
Is that good? We'll proceed, okay?
今日は七夕だから、悩みを願いに変えろ！ねぽらぼ、せーの、ねぽらぼの願いよー！
Today is Tanabata, so turn your troubles into wishes! NEPOLABO, ready, NEPOLABO's wishes!
ねぽらぼの願いよー！
NEPOLABO's wishes!
大変だこれ！
This is tough!
はい、という事をね、え、皆さん、大変いただいた、あの私たちのことかしら？悩みをね、今日はね、ねぽらぼが4人で解決していきたいと思います。はぁー！ちょっと待ってって！
Yes, so um, everyone, thank you so much for receiving... is it about us? Today, the four of us in NEPOLABO want to solve your troubles. Haah! Wait a minute!
勘弁して！勘弁して！
Spare me! Spare me!
今日七夕だから、今日七夕だから！
Today is Tanabata, because today is Tanabata!
はしゃぎすぎちゃった。まあ、ライブの日がね七夕当日だからね、なんかね、こう利益ありそう。
I got too excited. Well, since the live day is Tanabata itself, it seems like there'll be some profit.
あ、ご利益ある？あ、私ご利益。ご利益。ゴリラ、ゴリラ派！ゴリラ、ゴリラ派のオマルです！
Ah, there's divine favor? Ah, me, divine favor. Divine favor. Gorilla, gorilla faction! I'm Omaru of the gorilla, gorilla faction!
いいですか？ね、埋めてって言って？あ、動いていいですよ？
Is that good? Say "bury it"? Ah, you can move, okay?
えーということでね、今日は真剣に、はい、真剣にお悩みを解決していきたいと思います。はい！
Um, so today we want to sincerely, yes, sincerely solve your troubles. Yes!
そして、お悩みが解決することを大祈りするのでね、皆さんもね、よろしくおねがいしますよ、ちゃんと！おねがいします！はい！
And, since we pray greatly that your troubles will be resolved, everyone, please treat us well properly! Please! Yes!
はい！ふう、じゃあね、とりあえず、えー
Yes! Whew, well then, for now, um
どうしよう？どうしよう？皆さんのお悩みを聴くために移動します！
What should we do? What should we do? We'll move to listen to everyone's troubles!
はい、今日もねぽらぼ元気です！元気です！元気でしたねー！
Yes, NEPOLABO is energetic today too! Energetic! We were energetic!
まだ、あ、やめてください！
Still, ah, please stop!
とりあえず1つミルクしか勝たん
Anyway, only milk wins!
はい！という事で！わー！こちら移動してまいりました！
Yes! So! Wow! We have moved here!
ね、いまみんな必死にずっと喋ってたっていうのがめちゃめちゃもろいよね。聞こえた？聞こえたのかな？
See, the fact that everyone was desperately talking the whole time is so fragile, right? Did you hear it? Did you hear it?
聞こえてたっぽい？聞こえてたっぽい？あらら。決まらないな。
Sounded like you heard it? Sounded like you heard it? Oh my. It's not settled.
え、という事で皆さん、席に座ってください！はい！
Um, so everyone, please sit at your seats! Yes!
座るぞ！あ、待って、待ってどうした？ねねさん、ねねさん座るぞ！はい、流れで来てますよ。
Let's sit! Ah, wait, wait, what's wrong? Nene-san, Nene-san, sit! Yes, we're flowing with it.
座ってください！ねねがね、待機中にコメントしてたから
Please sit! Because Nene was commenting while waiting
あー、やめて！やめて！ぎりぎりまでねねとかが暴れてたから。
Ah, stop! Stop! Because Nene and others were rampaging right up until the edge.
ということでね。はい。
So, yes.
ハッシュタグ＃サープねぽらぼに願いをで寄せられたお悩みをみんな見ていきましょう！
Let's look at the troubles sent in with the hashtag #NEPOLABOWish!
イェーイ！イェーイ！はい、まずは、こちら！
Yay! Yay! Yes, first is this!
どーん！てでん！はい、じゃあこちらねねさんに感情を込めて読んでいただきましょう！
Boom! Tada! Yes, then let's have Nene-san read this with emotion!
はいですね。
Yes.
ファンネーム、みかんさん。高校最後の体育祭で団長になってしまった…どうしても緊張するし、なんか責任感を感じてしまいます…どうすればリラックス出来ますでしょうか？
Fan name: Mikan-san. I became the leader for the last sports festival of high school... I get so nervous and somehow feel a sense of responsibility... How can I relax?
なるほど。
I see.
ということでね、みかんさんは、え、団長になってしまったのでリラックスをする方法を知りたいということですね。なるほど。ちょっと、言い方が悪い。
So, Mikan-san wants to know how to relax since she became the leader. I see. Wait, your phrasing is bad.
ソラ、もうメイン張ってて、あ、せいじちゃんみたいな。
Sora, you're already playing the main, ah, like Seiji-chan.
あ、アルちゃん
Ah, Polka-chan,
ま、そう思ってさ、のどためるしかないべ
Well, thinking that, you just have to save your throat.
ちょっと、あの、前髪挙手制なんで
Wait, um, it's hand-raising for bangs...
え、てことでね、リラックスする方法ですよ！ちゃんと解決する方法考えてください。はい、誰かいますかー？
So, how to relax! Please think of a proper solution. Yes, anyone?
はーい！
Me!
はい、はい、はい、はい！ポルカさん！責任を感じろ！リラックスなんてするな！素晴らしい団長を全うしろ！わっしょい！
Yes, yes, yes, yes! Polka-san! Feel the responsibility! Don't relax! Fulfill your role as a great leader! Wasshoi!
あー、なんかバルタンだな、おもい、えー、圧がかかっていますが。もっと優しいね、あの、寄り添う系と。ねねさんどうぞ。
Ah, that's heavy... um, there's pressure. How about a gentler, more supportive approach? Nene-san, please.
はい！なんでだつの？おもずねねね！はい！団長なので代わりに濡れる先輩を召喚すればいいんじゃないかなと思いました。
Yes! Why stand? Omozunene! Yes! Since you're the leader, I thought you could summon a senior to get wet instead.
あー、いいじゃん！
Ah, that's good!
いい、それ。あーこれ、いいんじゃないですかー？
That's good. Ah, isn't this good?
はい、はい、来てくれるの？
Yes, yes, will they come?
牡丹さん。あのね、なんでもしまったという言い方からすると、あの、だらされた系だと思うので、あの、何があった場合責任をその、決めた人に押し付ければいいと思います。
Botan-san. Um, judging by the phrasing 'made to', I think it's a forced situation, so if anything happens, you should just shift the responsibility to the person who decided it.
えーー、そういう気分で、対処していけばいいと思います。
Umm, I think you should handle it with that kind of mindset.
えー、待って、だめじゃん、これ！
Wait, isn't that bad, this!
いや、下手か？ま、ネミーとしては
No, is that clumsy? Well, as Nemy,
まあ、ちょっとね、あのリラックスをするということで、皆さんリラックス普段どういう風に逆にしてるんですか？じゃあ。
Well, regarding relaxing, how do you guys usually relax, then?
はい！
Yes!
あ、これも挙手制、あ、なるほど。はい、ねねさん。牧場に行きます。
Ah, this is also hand-raising, oh I see. Yes, Nene-san. I go to the ranch.
はい、待って（笑）はい、牡丹さん。
Wait (laughs) Yes, Botan-san.
えーー、リラックス、こう言う時のリラックスの仕方は、あの、普段どういう風にリラックスしてるの？あ、もう、ゲームする！あ、なるほど、自分の好きなことする、それ。
Umm, relaxing, how do you relax at times like this? Ah, just play games! Ah, I see, doing what you like, that.
自分の好きなことしましょう。ちなみにポルカさんは普段、ちょっとやめてください、ポルカさん。
Let's do what you like. By the way, Polka-san usually... please stop, Polka-san.
ポルカさんは普段はどういう風なリラックスをするんですか？リラックスの方法、これ。ね、めでたい、めでたいじゃん！
How does Polka-san usually relax? The relaxation method, this. Hey, congrats, congrats!
これ、きもせ、きもせ、こわい、こわい、こういう感じで、何これ。
This is creepy, creepy, scary, scary, like this, what is this.
じゃあ、まあ、えー、まとめますと、まあ、リラックスをするために自分の好きなことをして、なおかつペットがいる場合はそれをめでる。ペットだったの？ってことでよろしいでしょうか？
Well, to sum it up, to relax, you do what you like, and if you have a pet, you adore it. It was a pet? Is that alright?
やったー、やったー。というわけで、みかんさんが無事リラックスできますように！はい、できますようにだ！
Yay, yay. So, may Mikan-san be able to relax safely! Yes, may she!
はい、てことでに、はい、次のえー、悩み、はい、こちらです！
Yes, so, yes, the next, um, concern, yes, here it is!
ワンネーム、ゆたんぽさんから頂きました！ありがとうございます！ねぽらぼライブが待ち遠しくて夜しか眠れなくて困っています！ねぽらぼの皆さんのお勧めの安眠方法を教えてください！
We received this from Yutanpo-san! Thank you! I'm so excited for the NePoLaBo live that I can only sleep at night and I'm troubled! Please tell us your recommended sleep methods!
めっちゃ寝てるじゃん！夜にちゃんと。これ、ツッコミ待ちのやつですね。もうこういうのはいいんですよ。寝れ、夜しか寝れない、お前ずっと寝てんじゃねえか、っていうツッコミを流すということで。
You're sleeping plenty! At night properly. This is waiting for a punchline. We don't need this. 'You can only sleep at night, haven't you been sleeping the whole time?' - just skimming past that punchline.
えっ、安眠方法？安眠方法？我々の方が逆に聞きたくない？うちらが解決するんだ、何言っての。
Eh, a sleep method? A sleep method? Don't we want to ask you instead? We're the ones solving it, what are you saying.
いや、だがしかし、我々結構夜遅くまで配信したりするからさ、ねえ、さーちゃんもだよ。
Well, but, we stream quite late at night sometimes, right, Saa-chan too.
なるほどね、私達も結構12時に寝るけどね。睡眠速度らしいね。ちゃんと寝れるの？二の回数で。ちゃんと寝れてるの？
I see, we also sleep around 12 usually. Sound sleep speed or something. Can you sleep properly? With two counts. Are you sleeping properly?
え、でも寝れますよ。でも、ねぽらぼライブに向けて待ってるんだったら、それは
Eh, but I can sleep. But if you're waiting for the NePoLaBo live, that is
私たちにとっては嬉しい悩みですから、そのままの気持ちで行ってって感じだけれど、起きてきてくれて、でも夜寝てるから寝るからね。
a happy problem for us, so keep that feeling as you go, but wake up, though you sleep at night so you sleep.
てことで、ポルカさん、この方の解決方法は？はい！えっと、えー、ゆたんぽが、えっと、眠れないようなぐらい楽しませるので、えっと、いっぱい寝てください！はい！安眠方法教えてくださいだけどね、寝てください。
So, Polka-san, what is your solution for this person? Yes! Um, Yutanpo, um, we'll make it fun enough that you can't sleep, so um, please sleep a lot! Yes! You asked for a sleep method, but please just sleep.
強いて言うと、あの、まぶたにあったかいののせるといいよ。あー、いい！
If I had to say, um, putting something warm on your eyelids is good. Ah, nice!
じゃあね、ゆたんぽさんが夜ゆっくり眠れますようにと、いうことで、いー。
So, may Yutanpo-san be able to sleep soundly at night, so...
眠れますように！って、何その、半端な付け方。
May you sleep soundly! What's with that half-hearted ending?
はい、それではね、次のね、お悩みはこちら！
Yes, then, the next concern is here!
4月から仕事の都合で数年海外へ行くことになりました。ねぽらぼの皆さんから新天地で頑張るリスナーさんへ応援の一言をお願いします！！！
Due to work, I will be going overseas for a few years starting in April. From the NePoLaBo members, please give a word of encouragement to our listener doing their best in a new place!!!
なるほど。これは解決というよりかは応援メッセージをひとこといただきたいということですね。じゃあねぽらぼで行きましょうか。はい、じゃあねさんから。
I see. Rather than a solution, this is asking for a word of encouragement message. Shall we go with NePoLaBo style? Yes, then Nene-san, please.
はい！頑張ってください！え、普通？普通だな。でもねねのことをいっぱいいっぱい考えながらいっぱい頑張ってね！
Yes! Do your best! Eh, normal? That's normal. But while thinking about Nene a whole lot, please do your best!
じゃあポルカさんお願いします！電機のアンペアとか、あの、気をつけてね！海外。
Then Polka-san, please! Be careful about the electrical amperage and stuff overseas!
じゃあね
See ya.
じゃあちょっと先にポルポルさんからいきましょうか
Well, let's start with Polpol-san first.
ま、海外、この方は海外ですけど、
Well, as for overseas, this person is going overseas,
ま新天地っていうことで引越しとかね、新しい環境に行くっていう方いらっしゃると思うので、
but since it's a new place, moving and going to a new environment, I think there are people like that,
とりあえず洗濯機と冷蔵庫と炊飯器がいいやつ買うといいです。
so for now, it's good to buy a good washing machine, fridge, and rice cooker.
洗濯機と冷蔵庫って！みんなガチじゃん！
A washing machine and fridge?! You guys are so serious!
えじゃあ、次ラミィのラミィのお願いね。
Well then, next is Lamy's... Lamy's request.
お願いします。かきやんさん、言うてほら。
Please. Kakiyan-san, look, as I said.
雪民マークもついてるから。ほんとだ。
You even have the Yukimin mark. True.
かきやんさん、頑張ってね、ラミィが応援してるよ、うん、ば！
Kakiyan-san, do your best, Lamy is cheering you on! Mwah!
何？
What?
なんかさあ
Something like...
なんか、そっちのラミィじゃない最新の方のラミィでやってよ。
Like, do it with the newest Lamy, not that other Lamy.
いやいや、最新のなによ？
No way, what do you mean by newest?
いや、何が代わりにやってあげる。いや、もう終わってから！
No, what, I'll do it for you. No, it's already over!
綺麗に閉めたところを
Right when I neatly wrapped it up—
雪民さん！
Yukimin-san!
雪民さん！やめてって！ポルカが応援してるよ！ちょっと、ちょっと、頑張ってもろて！
Yukimin-san! Stop it! Polka is cheering you on! Hang in there!
っていうことですね、頑張ってもろて、ねえねえ、え、海外でもね、頑張ってください。はい、頑張ってね。
And so, hang in there, hey hey, um, even overseas, please do your best. Yes, do your best.
はい、がんばれー！
Yes, good luck!
ということで次のお悩みは、こちら！
With that, the next concern is here!
5000兆円欲しい！！！！！
I want 5 trillion yen!!!!!!
はい、悩んでないですね。
Yeah, there's no worrying here.
欲望丸出しで頑張ってください。
Just go full greed and do your best.
あげません。
I won't give you any.
頑張ってください。
Do your best.
あげません、あげません。
I won't, I won't.
えーっと、これはどうしましょうかね。え、頑張れ。
Um, what should we do about this? Uh, do your best.
ししろ、ししろんからね。
From Shishiron, um.
応援メッセージを
An encouraging message—
甘いんじゃない？
Isn't that too soft?
ていうか自力で稼げるようになってください。
Or rather, learn to earn it on your own.
5000兆円！5000兆円！
5 trillion yen! 5 trillion yen!
5000兆円自力で稼ぐのはちょっと無理じゃないですか。
Earning 5 trillion yen on your own is a bit impossible, isn't it?
あげてください。
Give it to him.
え、そしたらその時はお布施してください。
Well, then give an offering at that time.
なんでだよ！
Why's that!
年々に3000兆円くだ……半分以上あげんだよ！
Give 3,000 trillion yen every year... you're giving away more than half!
すみません、すみません。
Sorry, sorry.
はい、じゃあ次のラミィいけますよ！い、次は、こちら！
Alright, now next is Lamy's turn! Um, next is this!
ずんさんですね。
It's Zun-san.
私は、勤務時間が長い仕事に就いています。
I work long hours.
そんな中で推し活もしたいし、寝る時間も欲しいので、24時間じゃ足りない状態です！
Amidst that, I want to support my oshi and also want sleep, so 24 hours just isn't enough!
上手な時間の使い方をぜひ教えていただければ幸いです！
I would be grateful if you could teach me how to use time well!
なるほど。
I see.
はい。枕にスピーカーをつけて、寝ながら睡眠学習！寝ながら学習を身に付けるばいいと思います。
Yes. Put a speaker on your pillow and do sleep learning while sleeping! I think it's good to acquire learning while sleeping.
寝ながら強いよ、睡眠の時に覚えるやつ。
Learning while sleeping is strong, the stuff you memorize while sleeping.
反論です。
Objection.
リピートじゃない！やめてください。
It's not a repeat! Please stop.
目は見えないと思います、それでは、耳でしか聴けないと思うんですけど、どうですか？
I think you can't see, so you can only listen with your ears, what do you think?
推しの可愛い姿は脳内補充できます。
You can mentally supplement your oshi's cute appearance.
はい、ということでね。
Yes, so,
あ、おまるさん静かになった。
Ah, Omaru-san became quiet.
これ以上はちょっとあの場外乱闘で、あのね、ネネとディベートするんでよろしくお願いします。
Beyond this is a bit of an out-of-bounds brawl, um, Nene and I are going to debate, so please look forward to it.
ということでね、じゃあカメラさんこっち向いていただいて、そのあとにね、場外乱闘していただいて、
And so, camera-san, please face this way, and after that, please have an out-of-bounds brawl,
このその間にね、場外乱闘。
And in the meantime, out-of-bounds brawl.
ええ、何ですかこれは？解決方法は結局何なんですか？何なんですか？
Eh, what is this? What on earth is the solution method? What is it?
ええと、タイムマシンに乗ればいいと思います。
Um, I think you should ride a time machine.
なに言ってんだよ！もうちょっとマシなんないの？
What are you saying! Isn't there something a bit better?
ええ、これは解決方法はない、上手な時間の使い方でしょ、でも。
Eh, there's no solution method for this, though it's about how to use time well.
なんですか？これはスケジュール組むしかないですね。
What is it? You have no choice but to build a schedule.
寝室をやめて、寝室パンチ！
Stop the bedroom, bedroom punch!
スケジュール組めじゃん！スケジュール組みましょう。組めじゃん！何時から何時は配信を見る時間、何時から何時は、
Build a schedule! Let's build a schedule. Build one! From what time to what time is watching streams, from what time to what time—
そうそう。確かにな。え、じゃああるじゃん！
That's right. True. Eh, then there is one!
ちょっとシシロンはズンさんにちょっとスケジュール組めって勝つ入れてあげたらいいじゃん。
Shishiron, why don't you give Zun-san a kick in the pants and tell them to build a schedule?
そうだね！勝つ、勝つ入れてあげて。
That's right! Give them a kick, give them a kick.
勤務時間長い仕事を変えてください。ええ！？
Change jobs with long working hours. Eh! ?
っていうか、短縮してください。ええ！？
Or rather, shorten them. Eh! ?
まずそこからじゃん。じゃあ、お願い。
Start from there. Well, please.
じゃあ、お願いしてください、可愛く。
Well, please ask them, cutely.
じゃあ、まあ、仕事はあんまり無理せず頑張ってください。はい。
Well, um, please do your best at work without pushing yourself too hard. Yes.
叶いますように、仕事が、じゃあ勤務時間が短くなりますように。はい！
May it come true, may your work... um, may your working hours become shorter. Yes!
はい、ありがとうございます。はい、じゃあ次の悩みはこちら。
Yes, thank you very much. Yes, now the next concern is here.
変わりましたね。はい。
It changed. Yes.
ファンネーム、え、タラクマさんですかね。ありがとうございます。はい、ありがとうございます。
Fan name, um, Tara-kuma-san. Thank you very much. Yes, thank you very much.
7月7日ですが、私の誕生日ですと。え、ほんと！？おめでとう！
It's July 7th, but it's my birthday. Eh, really?! Happy birthday!
え、今年の誕生日は何をして過ごせばハッピーになると思いますか？
Um, what should I do on my birthday this year to become happy?
ふりでしょう?
Is that a setup?
ふり?
A setup?
ふりでしょう!
It's a setup!
ええっと、何見てんのよ!
U-Um, what are you looking at?!
ネポラボライブを見たらいいと思います!
You should watch the Nepolabo Live!
是非こっちでね、ネポラボライブを見てください。
Be sure to check out the Nepolabo Live over here!
Tara-kumaさんの願いが掲って素敵なライブが見れますよー! にーっ!
May Tara-kuma's wish come true and you get to see a wonderful live! Yay!
えーっと、ドはドーナツのミさん、人間の顔と名前を覚えるのが苦手です、どうやったら覚えられるようになりますか?
E-Um, "Do is the donut's Mi-san": "I'm bad at remembering people's faces and names, how can I get better at remembering them?"
読んであげてください。
Please read it.
ええ、ざ、ざいんかお前、人の顔と名前を覚えるのが苦手です、どうやったら覚えられるようになりますか?
U-Um, "Zain," you damn fool— "I'm bad at remembering people's faces and names, how can I get better at remembering them?"
確かに!
Indeed!
ぱみ、めちゃめちゃ苦手だね。
Pami, you're super bad at it, right?
どういう感じで覚えていくのがいいのかな?これ得意な人逆に出るこの中で。
How should one go about remembering them? Is there anyone here who's actually good at it?
ねぇ、あのね、顔は、あ、違う、顔はすごい覚えるの。
Hey, you know, I remember faces really well—oh wait, I remember faces and—
喋ってる内容と顔は覚えるのに、名前だけなんか覚えられないの。
I remember faces and what they say, but for some reason I just can't remember names!
ねねは、なんか、頭の中であだ名つけて、あー、なんか、言っちゃわない?言っちゃう、言っちゃう、言っちゃう!
Nene kind of gives them a nickname in her head—ah, like, don't you end up saying it? You say it, you say it, you say it!
までも、その、紐付けするっていうのはね、記憶としては正しい、そうそう。特徴的なこととかね、すごく。
But still, associating things is correct for memory, right? Like having distinctive traits.
ええと、ま、このまま解決策まで話しちゃいますけど、ええと、ええと、相手も覚えてないことがあることがあります。
U-Um, well, to skip straight to the solution: um, sometimes the other person doesn't remember you either!
あ、なるほど! 逆に聞きたい、聞きたい、その時。
Ah, I see! I'd actually want to know what you do in that case.
あ、ええと、あ、あ、おまるぽるかです。
Ah, um, ah, ah, I'm Omaru Polka.
しまーす。あー、あー、おまるぽるかです、それです、即興が始まってたんです、今。すいません、すいません、すいません!
Hello. Ah, ah, I'm Omaru Polka, that's it, improvisation just started right now. Sorry, sorry, sorry!
あ、なるほど、ゆゆのらみです。あ、この間なんかすれ違いましたよね?みたいな。
Ah, I see, I'm Yukihana Lamy. "Ah, we crossed paths recently, didn't we?" like that.
ね!ね!ね!
Right! Right! Right!
めちゃくちゃ楽しかったですよね、あの時。またよろしくお願いしますって。
"It was so much fun back then, hope to work with you again."
褒めですよ。手に負わせる、もうこれしかない。
That's praise. Shifting the burden, there's nothing else!
いいじゃん。自分からは言い、言って、相手にいわせる、名前を話せるってことか。
That's good. Rather than saying it yourself, you make the other person say their name.
そう!相手がわかってないんだろうなって気を遣う、もう、あの自分の中で自分も、あ、やばいの、自分からも自己紹介を先に始まっちゃう、自分のこと忘れちゃってるんだみんな!
Exactly! Worrying that the other person might not remember you, and then you panic and start introducing yourself first because you think they've forgotten you!
この間はお世話になりました、あ、おまるぽるかですってね。そうそうそうそう。さすがですよ、らみさん。
"Thank you for taking care of me recently, ah, I'm Omaru Polka." Exactly, exactly. As expected of Lamy-san.
ということでさ、ぽるかさん、お願いしとけてください。
So Polka-san, please do the honors.
はい、では、ドーナツの美のそちらの、え、ドーナツの美の名前、人と顔が覚えられるようにポルカの解決さんでよろしくお願いします!
Yes, now, for "Donut's Mi-san's" concern: so that people's faces and names can be remembered, with Polka's solution, please take care of it!
さいきっけだな。
What a neat save.
はい、ありがとうございます!覚えられるように。ということでね、次のお悩みはこちら。
Yes, thank you very much! So that you can remember them. With that, our next concern is this.
お、ししろん!
Oh, Shishiron!
raraito、ししろん推し。はい。
"Raraito," Shishiron fan. Yes.
え、身近にホロライブをしている人がいなく、(いるだろ?) 知っている人が、え、知っている人が、
"There's no one around me who's into Hololive"—("There must be!")—"people who know,"—uh, "people who know"—
いなくて、語ることができません。(どうすればいいでしょう?) ホロライブ、(脳みそが崩れたら終わるぞ)
"aren't around, so I can't talk about it." (How should I do that?) Hololive, (if your brain breaks it's over)
しかします、しかします、(ブレインが崩れたら終わるぞ) ごめんなさい。
Let me re-read, let me re-read— (if the brain breaks it's over) Sorry!
え、かなりのコミュ障でネット界でも話すことができません。はい。というお悩みです。
"I have severe social anxiety and can't even talk about it online." Yes. That's the concern.
なるほど。身近に、まあ、ホロライブファンがちょっといないから、その直接その一緒に語り合いたいていうのができないみたいな。
I see. Since there aren't really any Hololive fans close by, you can't directly talk and share your passion together.
でもこれはさ、逆に、もう推しのこのししろんの良さを自分の友達にね、布教して巻き込んでいこう。そうそうそう、え、推し、この推し知ってる?
But on the other hand, why not evangelize the greatness of your oshi, Shishiron, to your own friends and drag them in? Exactly, like "Do you know this oshi?"
え、ちょっと待って、待って、待って!かっこがついてるよ、これ。
Wait, wait, wait! There are parentheses here, look.
(かなりのコミュ障でネット界でも話すことができません)って書いてあるよ。
It says "(I have severe social anxiety and can't even talk about it online)."
これ話でもね、あの、あれじゃないかな、やっぱり共通の趣味を持ってる人っていうのは、もう一言自分が、え、実の自分、あのししろんボタン押しててってなったら、そっからもう盛り上がっちゃうわけよ、早く。
But even so, isn't it that people who share common hobbies will immediately get excited the moment you say, "Actually, I'm pushing Botan Shishiro"?
あれじゃない?ハッシュタグ付ければいいんじゃない?
How about adding a hashtag?
今日も暇だな、ハッシュタグ「ししろん好き」と繋がりたい。それはどうなの?どうなんだろう、でもそれも勇気だな。
"Bored today, want to connect with hashtag #LoveShishiron." What's that like? I wonder, but that also takes courage.
そこから踏み出す?でもそれは結構ホロライブのさ、このDiscordサーバーとかさ、ファンサーバーみたいなの...
Taking a step from there? But you know, Hololive's Discord servers and fan servers...
それがだから、たぶん苦手なんだってわかる。
That's probably why they find it difficult, you see.
今、ホロライブの公式の方でもさ、ホロライブファン向けのアプリ作ってたり、いろいろしてるから、ちょっとそういうのを今後活用していって貰えたらいいんじゃないかなってちょっと会社のね、用意はしてあります。
Right now, on the official Hololive side, they're making apps for Hololive fans and stuff, so maybe you could make use of those in the future—well, the company has prepared that kind of thing.
よいしょ、よいしょ、よいしょ、よいしょ!ホロプラス活用してよー!ホロプラス活用してよー!
Yoisho, yoisho, yoisho! Make use of HoloPlus! Make use of HoloPlus!
稼ぎの方も上の方も言われました！
Earnings-wise, management told us too!
おつえください！
Please give us the solution!
じゃあだららいとさん、ホロライブアプリなど色々できますので、そちらの方活用してください。
So Raraito-san, you can do various things with the Hololive app, so please make use of that!
はーい、ありがとうございます！
Yes, thank you very much!
はい、ということで次のねみゃあこちら！
Okay, and now for the next one!
ででん！
Tada!
えー、レギルス中佐さん、中、中佐さん
Um, Regulus Chuusa-san... Chu-, Chuusa-san,
ごめんなさい！
I'm sorry!
まぁ崩れまくってますね！
You're totally falling apart!
え、ねぽらぼえ、なんだぞ、ねぽらぼえ
Nepolabo... what is Nepolabo...
二十歳上みたいな感じか
Like an adult, or something?
チケットを当てるために徳を積んでおきたいのですが、何をすればいいでしょうか？
To win tickets, I want to accumulate virtue. What should I do?
おおー
Ooh.
なるほど！
I see!
これは、じゃあ1人ずつ言ってこうか。
Shall we go around and give our answers one by one?
何やってるの？徳積んでるんだよ、特を。
What are you doing? I'm accumulating virtue.
際の瓦みたいじゃん。やめなさいよ！縁起悪いじゃん！
It looks like temple tiles. Stop it! That's bad luck!
やめなさい。ということで一人ずつねねさんからちょっと言っていただきましょうか。
Stop it. So let's hear from Nene-san one by one.
はい！えー、トイレには神様がいるらしいので、トイレ掃除をすればいいと思います。
Yes! Um, they say there's a god in the toilet, so cleaning it is good.
ああ、なるほどね！いいと思う、すごい。トイレの神様って何してくれるの？
Ah, I see! That's amazing. What does the toilet god do for you?
やめなさいよ。徳を積むのを叶えてくれる。えー、そうだの。
Stop it. They grant your accumulation of virtue. Ah, is that so?
ポルかさん、親孝行！はい、とてもいい！いいね！
Polka-san, filial piety! Yes, very good! Nice!
もうトイレ掃除、親孝行、もうこれで十分なのだでは。十分なのだでは、足りない！分かりました！
Toilet cleaning, filial piety, that's already plenty! That's not enough! Understood!
じゃあラミィいます。自分を大切にする。いい！
Then Lamy's turn. Cherish yourself. Great!
チケットを当てるために徳を積んでおきたいのですが、何をすればいいでしょうか？これはもうみんなの配信を見守る事です。おお、素晴らしい！
What should I do to accumulate virtue to win tickets? That is to watch over everyone's streams. Oh, wonderful!
ホロライブの配信を見守り、そして徳を積んでいく。えー、ということでね、レギルス中佐さん、
Watch Hololive streams and accumulate virtue. So, Regulus Chuusa-san,
えー、トイレ掃除をし、親孝行をし、ホロライブの配信を見、自分を大切にすることで、チケットが当たりますように！
Clean the toilet, practice filial piety, watch Hololive streams, and cherish yourself, so that you'll win tickets!
おお、大変だな！やる事いっぱいよ！当たるためにはこれ全部しないとダメじゃん！
Ooh, that's tough! So much to do! To win, you have to do all of this!
はい、ということで次のねみゃあこちら！ででん！
Okay, and now for the next one! Tada!
初任給を何に使えばいいか迷ってます、皆さんの初任給は何を買いましたか？
I'm hesitating on what to spend my first salary on. What did you buy with yours?
あ、じゃあこれはね、やっぱりホロライブに、こう、読んでいる、入る、入れるあいね！
Ah, well, this is, after all, reading/entering Hololive!
初めてお給料もらった時、みんな覚えてる？覚えてるよ！
When you first got your paycheck, does everyone remember? I remember!
ねー、買ったもん覚えている私。えっ、じゃあさ、何買った？いいマイク買いました。
Right, I remember what I bought. Eh, then what did you buy? I bought a good mic.
わあー！えらい！
Wow! Splendid!
機材を、ね、機材を綺麗に伝えたいってなって、機材を買った。機材だよ。機材。
Wanting to deliver equipment cleanly, I bought equipment. Equipment.
それはある。じゃあちょっと機材以外でみんな行こうか。じゃあ行く？機材以外？でもね、ラミィは、何にしたのかな？
That's true. Then let's go with things other than equipment. But Lamy, what did you get?
初任給で、あの、あ、でも２個あるな。どうしようどうしよう。
With my first salary, um, ah, but I have two things. What should I do?
じゃあちょっとみんなが言いそうな方は置いといて、ラミィね、あの家族にちょっといい、あの、物を買った。
Well, let's put aside what everyone might say. Lamy, um, bought something nice for her family.
えーー！おお、これが親孝行、親孝行としてますよラミィさんは。買いましたね、お屋敷に、いいな。
Ehh! Oh, that's filial piety, Lamy-san is doing filial piety. You bought it, for the mansion, nice.
お父様に買いました。お父様に！えー！
I bought it for my father. For your father! Ehh!
じゃあ、えー、ポルさん行こうか。
Then, um, shall Polka go?
ポルかも機材だったんだよな。あーでも、そうなるよね。機材の中でもでも色々あるんじゃん？マイクじゃなくてインターフェースを買いました。
Polka was equipment too. Within equipment, there are various things, right? Not a mic, I bought an interface.
なるほど！やっぱね、仕事道具やからな。もっといいの作りたいなって思って、あと歌ってみたとかに費やしましたね。
I see! After all, it's a work tool. I wanted to make something better, and I spent it on cover songs.
それはあるね。じゃあ最後ねねさん締めてください。
That's true. Then Nene-san, please wrap it up.
えー、ねね、買ったものとかママにちょっといいもの買ったし、で、今総じて残ってるのは、ホロライブ入ってお給料もらってから神社に行った時、ご縁じゃなくて500倍ご縁が欲しいと思って500円、
Nene bought things, bought something nice for mom, and what remains overall is, when I went to the shrine after joining Hololive and getting my paycheck, thinking I wanted 500 times the connection rather than 5-yen, 500 yen...
500円！投げたの！？え？え、これ、500円期待されてんのかな？みたいないたな。
500 yen! You threw 500 yen?! Eh? Eh, is 500 yen expected here? Something like that.
うん、500倍のご縁がありますようにって、100倍じゃ、
Yeah, 'May there be 500 times the connection,' 100 times...
いや、私もね、そっちの方がいいし、500円玉、神様も戸惑うよ、500円って言ってたら、500円玉！
No, I'd prefer that too, 500-yen coin, even the god would be puzzled if you say 500 yen, a 500-yen coin!
ちょっと贅沢！ちょっと、ちょっとおバカな。この子どうしようみたいなね。
A bit extravagant! A bit, a bit silly. Like 'What should I do with this kid?'
でもね、あれだよね、ラミィさん、あれだよ、ねねと一緒にちょっとお買い物とか行ったよね。行ったよね、行って。お揃いのものとか買って、すごい高いわけじゃないけど...
But you know, Lamy-san, you went shopping with Nene. You went, right? You went, bought matching things, not super expensive, but...
何想像した？
What did you imagine?
いや、いつも下着の話してるんで
Well, we're always talking about underwear...
ファンネーム：熱上げシート。初給料を何に使えばいいか迷ってます。皆さんの初給料は何を買いましたか？
Fan name: Heat-Raising Sheet. "I'm wondering what to spend my first salary on. What did you all buy with yours?"
お揃いのバッグとか買った
We bought matching bags or something.
というわけで、じゃあちょっとねねさんに締めてもらいましょうか。
With that said, let's have Nene wrap this up.
はい！えっと、熱上げシートさん！
Yes! Um, Heat-Raising Sheet-san!
初のお給料は、えー、ねぽらぼのライブにチケットを申し込んだり、
Your first salary... um, applying for Nepolabo live tickets,
あと、えっと、みんなに会いに来て、えっと、えっと、えっと、メンバーシップに入んない？どうしようか？
and um, coming to see everyone, um... joining the membership? What should we do?
発売即終了。いいね！ありがとうございます！
Sold out instantly. Nice! Thank you very much!
ライブチケットとかもね、意外と使えますんで。
Live tickets and things can actually be quite useful too.
サポートが（言うの）
As support would say...
使えますよ。ありがとうございます。
"They're useful." Thank you very much!
素敵な初給料のね、解説になりますように！熱上げシートさんが後悔しないように頑張るよ。
May this be a wonderful analysis of your first salary! Work hard so you don't regret it, Heat-Raising Sheet-san.
ということで、次の お悩みはこちら！
And with that, our next concern is here!
ファンネーム：増水はよいぞ。ガチ目の悩みだと。人の前で振る舞い続けて、自分が何がわからなくなってしまったことです。配信を見てる時の自分と日常で他の人と接している時の自分が違いすぎてわかりません。上手くははいっているんですが、なんとなくモヤモヤするのでねぽらぼの皆さん助けて〜
Fan name: Rising Water is Good. This is a serious concern: "By continuing to act in front of people, I've lost sight of who I am. The me watching streams and the me interacting with others in daily life are too different to understand. Things are going well, but I feel vaguely uneasy—please help me, Nepolabo!"
ガチ目の悩みだと、人の前で振る舞い続けて自分が何かわからなくなってしまったことです。配信を見てる時の自分と日常の他の人と接してる時の自分が違いすぎてなんかわかりません。上手くはいってるんですが、なんとなくモヤモヤするのでねぽらぼの皆さん助けて！
"A serious concern: by continuing to act in front of people, I've lost sight of who I am. The me watching streams and the me interacting with others in daily life are too different. Things are going well, but I feel vaguely uneasy—please help me, Nepolabo!"
これはガチですね。でもね、らみぃは思うんだけど、こうやってみんなと一緒にいる時のらみぃもらみぃだし、一人でスーってなってる時のらみぃもらみぃだし、どれが本当とかじゃないのかな。
That is serious. But Lamy thinks, the Lamy who is here with everyone is Lamy, and the Lamy who is quietly by herself is also Lamy. Maybe none of them is more "real" than the other.
全部が自分だ。そう、全部が自分だと思うから。
They're all yourself. Since they're all you,
それは、どれかにしたいんだかもよ、でも。え、どれか一個に？でもだってオマルンがさ、今のこのテンション24時間やってる...
maybe you want to narrow it down to just one. Into just one? But Omalun, if you maintained this exact energy 24/7...
これよ！ねぽらぼみんな助けて！それこそオマルンもこの元気のオマルンもオマルンだし、ちょっと落ち着いてる時のオマルンもオマルンなわけじゃん。
Exactly! Nepolabo, everyone help! Omalun with this high energy is Omalun, and Omalun when she's a bit calm is also Omalun.
確かに。だからやっぱり全部ひっくるめて増水はよいぞさんなのだではないかとかみは思うのですが。
True. So I feel like Rising Water is Good-san is all of those things combined.
みなさんはどう思いますか？ え、どうしようかな？
What do you all think? Uh, what should we do?
でも、なんとなくモヤモヤしてるらしいので。
But since they seem to feel vaguely uneasy,
なるほどね、ちょっとじゃあザバッと切ってもらいましょうか、獅子白に。
I see. Then let's have Shishiro cut right through it.
いいね。じゃあもうこれ他の人と接している時の自分が違いすぎてわかりません。ほら、でも無理に分かろうとしなくていいんじゃないでしょう。
Sure. "The me interacting with others is too different to understand." Well, you don't have to force yourself to understand it.
なので、だからさっきのらみぃちゃんの借りると、全部が自分なので、なんか、そんな深くなんか考えなくていいのかな。
So, borrowing Lamy's earlier point, they're all you, so maybe you don't need to think about it too deeply.
あ、さっきのおまるんに近いんだけど、ぶっちゃけ他の他人野人ってそこまで自分のことあんまり深く考えてないからさ、
It's close to what Omalun said earlier, but honestly, other people don't think that deeply about you anyway,
まあ正直なところ、他人は自分のこと気にしてないから、逆に自分も気にしないっていうのは大事かな。
so honestly, since other people aren't worried about you, it's important not to worry about yourself too much either.
増水、そう、増水、溜めて、まあ上手いことはね、置いときましょう、気にしない、全部自分です。
Rising Water, yeah, Rising Water, store it up... well, let's leave the clever stuff aside, don't worry about it, it's all you.
はい、えー、増水はよいぞ、えー、なんとなくモヤモヤすることがなくなるようにするには、ポルカのペルソナというオリジナル曲を聴いてください。
Yes, um, Rising Water is Good—um, to make that vague uneasiness go away, please listen to Polka's original song "Persona."
そう水じゃないのか！どうすいじゃないのか。
It's not "zosui" (rice porridge)! Not zosui!
ファンネーム：ペンタン皇帝。頑張らないといけないのに、体が動かない、頑張れないって時に、頑張る方法が知りたいです！
Fan name: Pentan Emperor. "I need to work hard, but my body won't move and I can't push myself. I want to know how to motivate myself when I can't!"
頑張らないといけないのに体が動かない、頑張れないって時に頑張る方法が知りたいです。頑張るな。頑張るな。知りたいです。
"I need to work hard, but my body won't move..." "Don't work hard." "Don't work hard." "I want to know."
頑張るな！頑張るなは一択だなこれ。頑張るなよ。そう。
Don't work hard! "Don't work hard" is the only choice here. Don't work hard. Exactly.
だから体が動かない時点で、もう無理してんだよね。
So the moment your body won't move, you're already pushing yourself too hard.
もう休んで、休んで。休みだよ、休み。休め、休め。
Just rest, rest. It's rest time, rest. Take a break, take a break.
いやでも頑張っちゃダメだと思うよ、正直は。飲み物、何かしらのえ、それはエナジー系の...
But honestly, I think you shouldn't push yourself. Drinks, something like... energy drinks...
ただこれ、頑張らないといけないのにの、頑張らないといけない理由による...
But this depends on the reason why you "have" to work hard...
本当に、本当に頑張らないといけない時と、実はそこまで頑張らなくてもよかった時ってあるじゃん。
There are times when you truly, genuinely have to work hard, and times when you actually didn't need to push yourself that much.
あのね、真面目な人ほどね、何でもかんでも頑張るものよって思っちゃうじゃん。だからあるある。あるある、だから。
You know, the more serious a person is, the more they feel they have to work hard at everything. So that's so relatable. Exactly.
あるある。だからね、ほんと、お前ね、聞いてあげて、ねえ、白銀に聞いてあげて。
Relatable. So yeah, really, listen to her, hey, listen to Shirogane.
そうだよ、だから本当にこれ今頑張らないといけない時なのかってまず考えるのが大事かなと、個人的には思うんだけど、ものことのね、優先順位をつけて、ま、これが本当に大事、大事なことなのか、今やらなければならないのかっていうのはね、大事だと思う。
Exactly. So personally, I think the important thing is to first consider whether this is truly a time you need to push yourself, prioritize things, and figure out if it's genuinely important or something that must be done right now.
とりまえずでも、うちからしたら、多分もう休んでいいと思います。はい、そうだね。まあ、うちとしてはもう寝ろっていうことですね。
But anyway, from our perspective, I think you can probably just rest already. Yeah, exactly. Well, for us, it basically means "go to sleep."
確かに。ということで、ペンタン皇帝さんの、お悩みが...
True. With that, Pentan Emperor-san's concern...
なんとか解決しますように！
May we somehow solve it!
しますように！
May we!
睡眠80%で生きていけ。
Live on 80% sleep.
でも大事よね、それね。
That's important, though.
休め！休め！寝ろ！休め！
Rest! Rest! Go to sleep! Rest!
元気なんだよなー。
You're full of energy.
てことで、次の悩みは、こちら。
With that said, next up is this concern.
ファンネーム：wadachi(本物)@あくあクルー の方からいただきました。
Received from wadachi (Real) @ Aqua Crew.
ねぽらぼのみなさん、こんばんはー！
Ne-po-la-bo, good evening!
リア友がすごくストレスを抱えて悩んでいるのですが、
My real-life friend is dealing with a lot of stress and worrying.
ねぽらぼのみなさんはどうやってストレスを発散していますか？
How do you guys vent your stress?
教えていただけると幸いです m(_ _)m
I'd appreciate it if you could tell me m(_ _)m
なるほど！
I see!
これは、ストレス発散方法、一人ずついってこうか。
Let's go one by one with stress-relief methods.
ねね、ストレス！暴飲暴食！
Nene, stress! Binge eating and drinking!
体に良くない。
It's bad for your body.
でも、たまに、
But, once in a while...
たまにするにはいいんじゃない？暴飲暴食。
Isn't it okay to do it once in a while? Binge eating.
いいと思います。すごいスッキリする。
I think it's good. It's super refreshing.
ポルカさんがね、なんかそうじゃないんだよなみたいな、こっち側なみたいな。
Polka-san, like, is it not like that? Like on this side.
物欲解放！
Desire release!
同じじゃん！いっしょじゃねえかよ。
It's the same! Aren't they the same thing?!
ラミィは？ラミィは？
What about Lamy? Lamy?
ラミィはね、あのさっきみんなで話してたけど、あの、バカバカ話をする。
Lamy, well, we were all talking earlier, but, um, talking foolish nonsense.
友達がなんかこう結構真面目なことを色々考えて、私違ったりするので、頭からっぽにして、
Friends think about serious things and I'm different, so emptying my head,
あー、なるほどね、友達の相談ってさっき会話の内容…
Ah, I see, friend consultations, conversation content from earlier...
言うな言うな！みたいなのもね、ストレス解消にいいのかなと思います。
"Don't say it! Don't say it!" Stuff like that might be good for stress relief.
はい。次。
Yes. Next.
私のね、ストレス発散はね、寝る。
My stress relief is sleeping.
次の日になってたら、結構忘れているだけあるから、睡眠は大事、睡眠は大事だと思うよ。
If it becomes the next day, you often just forget it, so sleep is important, I think sleep is important.
やっぱ寝不足なときもさ、なんか思考回路がふわふわしてさ、なんか変なこと考えちゃったりとかもするもんね。
When you're sleep-deprived, your train of thought gets fuzzy, and you end up thinking weird things.
ぐっすり寝る、なんか寝る多いな、今日解決方法。
Sleeping soundly... sleeping a lot today for solution methods.
寝るって大事なんだよ、しっかり寝れば。
Sleeping is important, if you sleep properly.
てことて、じゃあねねさんまとめてください。
So, Nene-san, please summarize.
えっと、わだちさんは、今日からストレスが溜まったら暴飲暴食をして、物欲をすべて解放して、寝ながら、ゼロ会話の内容ゼロの話をして、笑おう！ね？やばい、ストレス！できますように！できますように！
Um, Wadachi-san, starting today, when stress piles up, binge eat and drink, release all your desires, sleep while talking about zero conversation content, and laugh! Right? Oh no, stress! May you be able to! May you be able to!
ええ、ということでね、次の悩みは、こちら。
So, the next concern is this.
ちょっとした悩みなのですが、
It's a minor concern, but...
怒りが込み上げてきた際に、落ち着かせる方法は何かありますか？
when anger wells up, is there any way to calm down?
ファンネーム：シキシキ [しらしん大好きSSRB] の方からいただきました。
Received from fan name: Shikishiki [Shira-shin loving SSRB].
ちょっとした悩みなのですが、怒りが込み上げてきた際に、落ち着かせる方法は何かありますか？
It's a minor concern, but when anger wells up, is there any way to calm down?
え、使い古してボロボロになったタオルを切り刻む！
Um, chopping up a worn-out, tattered towel!
ちょっとマジでやめてやめて。
Seriously, stop, stop.
なんかちょっとねねちゃん闇深いな、何や。
Nene-chan seems kind of dark, what's that.
なんか、ねねもう使わない割れかけの食器とかも終わってそうじゃない、そこらへん。
Like, Nene, isn't chipped tableware that you don't use anymore already broken around there?
あ、でも、あるからね、そういう施設ね。
Ah, but they exist, facilities like that.
ある、ある、ある。あの、使わ、使われないゴミになってしまった、ものを投げる、割る場所が、割る場所があるんです。
There are, there are. There are places where you can throw and smash things that have become unused trash.
面白そうな場所あるじゃん。そうなんだよね、人気施設。
There's an interesting place. That's right, popular facilities.
ねねちゃん、今やろうとした、今シキシキのこと思い出して、たまってるねねちゃん、ちょっとたまってるでしょ。
Nene-chan, you just tried to do it, remembering Shikishiki, Nene-chan has stuff piled up, you have some piled up.
シキシキのことを思い出して！
Remembering Shikishiki!
じゃあ、後でね、悩み聞くわ。わかった。
Well, I'll listen to your troubles later. Understood.
シキシキのことも思い出して。
Remembering Shikishiki as well.
あと暴飲暴食しような、物言いもしような、なんかゼロの話しような、よね！
And let's binge eat and drink, and talk about zero things, right!
えっと、なんだっけ？怒り、怒りが込み上げてきた、落ち着かせる方法？
Um, what was it? Anger, when anger wells up, how to calm down?
ラミィは、でも、ラミィがあんまり怒り、確かにあんまり怒んないからさ。
Lamy, though—Lamy doesn't really get angry, truly doesn't really get angry, so.
なんだろうな、でも、わかんない、ごめん、わかんないかも。
I wonder what it is, but I don't know, sorry, maybe I don't know.
怒りが湧かない方法は？
What's a way not to generate anger?
逆にね、心を広く持つ。同じ、同じ、同じ。
On the flip side, keep an open heart. Same, same, same.
あのポルカも怒んないから、あの、心を広く持つしか、ないと思う。
Polka doesn't get angry either, so, I think keeping an open heart is the only way.
その広く持つって具体的にどうやったらいいんですか？
How specifically do you do that, keeping an open heart?
え、別に、ね、ちっぽけなことですから。
Well, besides, you know, it's trivial things.
宇宙とかね、銀河系規模で見たら。
If you look at it on the scale of the universe or the galaxy.
え、違うよ、自分のは、あ、やっちゃったなとか、ずっと…
Eh, no, my own, ah, I messed up, or constantly...
七夕の奇跡の様に 5期生とみんなが集う場。
Like a Tanabata miracle, a gathering place for the 5th Gen and everyone.
それぞれの夢と願いがひとつになった瞬間、新しい輝きが生まれる。
The moment when each dream and wish become one, a new radiance is born.
一生の思い出となるかけがえの無い一夜をプレゼント。
Presenting an irreplaceable night that will become a lifelong memory.
hololive 5th generation live Twinkle 4 You
キービジュアルイラスト：しぐお
[Key Visual Illustration: Shiguo]
待ってちょっと聞いて聞いて。チケットだよ。
Wait, wait, listen, listen, tickets are...
はい、これ大事な情報なのでみんなよく聞いてください。
Ah, this is important info, everybody listen up!
はい、てことで、
So,
現地会場チケットは本日このあと21時から、
In-person venue tickets go on sale today starting at 21:00!
早いこのあと？
Wait, this early?
そうです。1次先行受付が開始されます。
That's right, the first-round advance ticket sales start!
わあ！いぇーい！
Yay!
え、ちなみにこれ大事なことなんですが、
Now, this is an important detail.
はい、1次先行はホロライブ公式ファンクラブ会員の方のみが応募可能なので、
The first-round advance tickets are only available to Hololive Official Fan Club members!
この機会にぜひぜひ登録をお願いします。
So make sure to sign up for membership!
お願いします！
Please!
同じく21時から配信チケットも受付開始なので、現地に行くのが難しいよっていう方もね、
Also starting at 21:00 today, streaming tickets will also go on sale.
こちら要チェックとなっております。
These are also available to check out.
おうちから応援してくれたら嬉しい！
We'd love for you to support us!
詳しくは概要欄から公演の特設サイト、各種チケット販売ページを確認お願いします！
For details, please check the concert's special website and ticket sales pages.
あ、いまコメントの固定にもなったんじゃない？
Oh, right, they're pinned in the chat now, aren't they?
あ、スタッフさんがおてしてもらって。
Oh, the mods pinned them for us!
ありがとうございます。まだまだここで終わるわけじゃないので、
Thank you! But we're not done yet,
まだあるんですよ。お願いします！
There's more, please!
キービジュアルも公開されたので、なんと、え、ライブグッズも発売でーす！
And 3D visuals were just released, so guess what? Live merch is also available now!
はい、じゃあちょっと順番に行きましょう。
So let's go through them in order.
はい、まず最初こちら応援セット！
First up is the Support Set!
Tシャツ、うちわライト、推しタオルがセットになったライブには欠かせない応援セットとなっております。
It includes a T-shirt, uchiwa light, and face towel—an absolute must-have set for the live!
ご購入特典にはオリジナルの缶バッジがついてくるのでぜひゲットしてください。
And buying this set comes with an original can badge, so make sure to get yours!
この缶バッジめちゃんこ大きいんですよ。このぐらい？
And this can badge is huge! Look at this!
ねえ、この、このぐらい。おにぎりぐらい？
Like a giant rice ball!
ちなみにちょっと左上に先行発送って書いてあるんですが、これちょっとあとで説明するので、
By the way, it says "advance shipping" in the top left, but I'll explain that later.
とりあえずこれ応援セットということで今はね、頭に置いてください。
For now, just remember this as the Support Set!
はい、そして応援セットに入っているアイテムは、なんと単品でも販売いたします！
Next up, Nene-chan, please! And items in the support set can also be purchased individually!
まずはうちわライト！
Starting with the uchiwa light.
これめっっちゃいいの！可愛い！
This is so cute!
これめっちゃいいよ、本当にこれめっちゃいい。
It really is super good!
ちゃんとね、青げたよね。青く光る。
It glows blue properly, right?
でしかも推しも推せるライブ特製のうちわライトになります。
And you can also push the light colors! It's a live-specific uchiwa light.
ちなみにあの点灯時の色これ今青だけど、ちゃんとうねねの色はネポラボカラーと全色っていうかそのテーマカラーからテーマカラーからね。
By the way, the light color is just blue here, but it actually has colors for all 5th gen members based on the theme colors.
当日会でも配信でもこのね、うちわライトつけて応援してくれたらなと思います。
We hope you'll bring this uchiwa light to cheer us on at the venue or during the stream!
そしてライブTシャツ、おもてにはライブのロゴドーンっていう感じにして、裏はねねたち5期のメンバーの名前がプリントされていて、ライブの日付まで入っているのでね、アイテムにぴったりでございます。
And for the live T-shirt, the front features the live logo, and the back has the names of all 5 members of 5th Gen and the live date printed on it, making it the perfect item for the live!
記念になります。じゃあ次おまるちゃん、スライドジャーン。
Alright, next up, Polka! Let's slide!
はい、こちらですね、次マフラータオル。こちらネポラボたちのお名前が大きくデザインされている推しタオルとなっております。
Next up is the muffler towel, featuring a big design of Nepolabo's name and the oshi towel!
会場でね掲げちゃってね、もうみんなのお店もう五期生推しの人の全分頭まで、全部。
If you wave this at the venue, all the oshi-oshi people will have their heads covered in sweat!
すごいネポラボ推しやってね。
It really shows you're a true Nepolabo fan!
これねはっきり分かるからね、マジで嬉しい。
It's super clear so you can really tell, which is awesome!
あのこれいいと思います。本当汗、なんかさ、汗が出るからさこれどうしようね、最初ラミーにして次ネネにしてみたいな。
Sweat comes out, so how should we do it? Start with Lamy, then Nene?
曲によって変えたりね、それいいですね。
Depending on the song? That's nice!
あ、ねねさんお顔変えてますね。いいですね、はい。
Nene-chan changed her face!
はい、次はこちら右ですね、みんなのはランダムだんたくふうアクリルキーホルダー。こちらは私たちで願いね、叶えたい願い、そしてみんなと叶えたい願いをメンバーそれぞれ書き下ろしました。
And next is the right side, the random acrylic keyholder! These are packed with wishes we want to come true with everyone, so we each designed our own!
まあランダムになっていますけど、中身はねゲットしてのお楽しみなんでみんなと交換したりとかしてぜひ全種類コンプリートしてください。
They are random, but collecting them all lets you exchange them with others, so we hope you get the whole set!
ね、もと、はい。
Yes, absolutely!
ということでここまで紹介した応援セットうちわライト、Tシャツ、マフラータオル、ランダム短冊風キーホルダー、これが先行発送アイテムです。
So those are the support set items: the uchiwa light, T-shirt, muffler towel, and random acrylic keyholder.
ライブ当日までに届きます。大切、これ大切。
They arrive by the live, so please get them!
あのこっちをね、あの入れてください。あのそれ以外は、えっとこれはあ、そうそうそそう、とりあえずこれが先行いらっしゃいますので。会場配信で身につけてください。
Make sure to include those in your cart! And except for those, wait, ah, those—well, anyway, those are the advance items delivered in time for the live!
はい、ここからは受注販売の商品となります。
And now, onto made-to-order goods!
まずは、こちらさっきねラミーとこ最初に持ってたちんちゃく。今ねちょっと持ってないんですけど。
First, the pouch we showed earlier, the drawstring pouch!
これがね、あの同じデザインで作られておりまして、おしとお皿にして色んなところに持ち歩いてください。
This drawstring pouch is made with the same design, perfect for carrying around your oshi goods!
そして、次はトートバッグ。これいいよね。普段使いのトートバッグになっておりまして、肩からかけてもよし、手で持つもよしということで、新しい枠が欲しいなと思っているそこあなた！
Next is the tote bag, which is super cute! You can carry it over your shoulder or by hand, perfect for when you need a little extra bag!
結構、もの怪しそうだった。わかる、分かってるね、めっちゃある。学生さんお喜びのやつ。はい、この機会を、お見、お見、お見逃しなく！
Wait, did someone drop something? Well, anyway, please check them out!
そして、
And,
モチーフチャーム！
the motif charm!
これね、聞いてください。
Listen to this, please.
リハーサルのときはモチーフチャーフって言ってたのに
During rehearsals, you kept saying "motif chauf,"
みんなモチーフチャームって言ったかね、はい。
but everyone else said "motif charm," right?
モチーフチャーム！
Motif charm!
この画像だとね、ちょっと分かりづらいと思うんですけど、
In this image it might be a bit hard to tell, but
ガラス風になっていて、すごくお洒落な感じとなっております。
it has a glass-like finish and looks super stylish.
付けってね、めっちゃ綺麗だった。
And when attached, it looked gorgeous.
これね、1個ずつ外して付けることもできるのでね、あの、さりげなくこう、スマホだったりこのトートバッグだったり巾着だったりね、
You can detach them one by one, so you can subtly attach them to your phone, tote bag, or pouch...
そう、これ1個1個分けられるからなんか自分がこの並び順にしたいみたいなね。
Yeah, since you can separate them individually, you can arrange the order however you want.
これはめちゃくちゃ綺麗にキラキラって感じとなっておりますので、色んなところにつけてみてください。
They have a really lovely, sparkly finish, so please try attaching them to various places!
そして、次はこちらを見ます。
And next, let's look at this.
タペストリーがアクリルスタンドです。
Tapestries and acrylic stands!
どーん！
Ta-da!
これね、ライブのイラストを使ったグッズとなっております。
These are goods featuring the live performance illustrations.
タペストリーはですね、発色が良くてもうすごくお勧めです。かわいいかった。ね。
The tapestries have great color saturation and are super recommended. So cute, right?
で、アクリルスタンドは全員分を集めると大きなジオラマになりますので、是非あの4つ集めて並べて飾ってください。
And if you collect all the acrylic stands, they form a huge diorama, so please collect all four and display them lined up!
立体になってるんだよね、アクリルスタンドが。立体になってるんで。
They're three-dimensional, right? The acrylic stands are 3D.
4人で並べて並べるとすごく迫力があったね、よかった。奥行きも。
Lining all four up gives it so much presence. It's great. And the depth too!
そこにね、ポラボが居るみたいな感じだったね。
It felt like Polabo was actually right there.
今回のこの森ダックスさんのライブ紹介、あのグッズの紹介になるんですけれど、
So this is an introduction to the live goods...
ええと、今日の21時から、あのホロライブオフィシャルショップで販売するので要チェックしてください。
Starting today at 21:00, they'll be sold on the official Hololive shop, so check it out.
はい、ここからじゃあさっきのちょっと注意事項が、結構ね難しいからね。よく聞いてください。まず1つ目。
Now, the precautions from earlier are a bit tricky, so please listen closely. First one.
先行発送グッズと受注販売グッズを一緒に、あの紹介したんですけれども、
We introduced pre-order shipping goods and made-to-order goods together, but...
こちら両方一緒に買うと、あの、受注販売グッズが届く日に届いてしまうため、その前に届かないというちょっと注意、そうなんですよ、難しいんです。
if you buy both together, they'll arrive on the delivery date of the made-to-order items, meaning they won't arrive before [the live]—that's a warning. Yeah, it's tricky.
ええと、同一会計で先行発送グッズと受注販売グッズを一緒に買わないように、先行発送グッズが欲しい方、ライブ前にグッズが欲しいという方は、別々に買って頂けたら嬉しいです。
So, to avoid buying pre-shipment and made-to-order goods in the same transaction—if you want pre-shipment goods before the live, please buy them separately.
会計を別々にすれば大丈夫。会計を分けて頂ければ大丈夫なんですけれども、同時に、あの受注分と先行分を買ってしまうと、受注分に合わせてあの発送されてしまいますので、どっちも欲しいけど先行が先に欲しい方は分けてお会計してください。
Splitting the checkouts is fine. As long as you separate them it's fine, but if you buy both at once, they'll ship together with the made-to-order batch. So if you want both but want pre-shipment first, check out separately.
要はね、ライブに向けて欲しい方は、先行だけまずお買い物して、で、そのあと受注を買えば大丈夫っていうことですね。分かっておりますので、これだけちょっと注意していただけたら嬉しいです。
Basically, if you want them in time for the live, buy the pre-shipment items first, and then buy the made-to-order ones. Just please keep this in mind!
はい、そして2つ目、先行発送グッズなんですけど、残念ながら数に限りがありまして、在庫がなくなりましたら、あの、販売終了になってしまいますのでご注意ください。
And second, for the pre-shipment goods, unfortunately quantities are limited, so once stock runs out, sales will end.
でもね、急ぎすぎて、その受注と先行、そう、そういうやつ。ちょっと勘違いしないようにお気をつけください。
Just be careful not to rush and mix up the made-to-order and pre-shipment items.
まずはね、先行、そう、先行商品が欲しいものがあれば、それを先に買うっていうのがおすすめって感じですね。
So if there are any pre-shipment items you want, buying those first is recommended.
で、詳しくはですね、この後公開される特設ページで注意事項も、あの、ありますので、あの、ちょっとしっかり読んでから申し込んでいただければ、
For details, there will be notes on the special page published later, so please read them carefully before applying.
要チェックで嬉しいです。白上さん分かりやすい説明ありがとう。
Please check it out! Fubuki-san, thank you for the clear explanation.
さあ、ライブ7月7日から始まるホルライブシティのツアー企画。
Now, starting July 7th, the Hololive City tour project!
で、ツインクルフォーユーの開催に合わせたツアーブラン、ねっぽらぼプランがご提供されることになりました。
And coinciding with "Twinkle 4 You," the "Neppolabo Plan" tour package will be offered!
やった！ご提供されることが...噛んじゃった。
Yay! Being offered— I stumbled.
体験の期間中にこのプランに参加すると、ねにたち、ねっぽらぼからのメッセージボイスとかがついてくるらしいので、ぜひチェックしてください。
If you participate in this plan during the period, you'll get message voices from us Neppolabo, so be sure to check it out!
ノベルティ付きワンパス、ねえこれワンパスがあったら乗り物乗り放題だからね。なるほど、ランドの方のってこと？ランド？あ、ちょっと語弊があった。語弊がある、語弊がある。東京ドームシティの乗り物のりものってことね。
A one-day pass with novelties. Oh, if you have this pass, you can ride the attractions as much as you want! Ah, Land? Wait, that was misleading. Misleading! I mean the rides at Tokyo Dome City.
ビッグオーに乗ってほしい。ビッグオー5回ぐらい乗ってほしい。絶叫コースター？観覧車だよ。あ、観覧車？絶叫しても怖いよね。ドルフィンのやつめちゃくちゃ怖くて面白い。
You should ride the Big O. Ride it about 5 times! A screaming coaster? It's a Ferris wheel. Ah, Ferris wheel? Even a Ferris wheel is scary when you scream. The Dolphin one is super scary and funny.
詳細版は明日9月1日...あ、8月1日からホルライブシティの公式サイトで公開になります。
Details will be announced tomorrow— August 1st on the official Hololive City website.
楽しみだね！
We're looking forward to it!
とかもね、なんか、いっちゃいけないそんなことをみんなやっぱいっちゃうそう、ことがあるから
You know, sometimes people accidentally say things they shouldn't...
ここは台本を読みながら、それでも全力告知をしましょう！
We'll read the script while giving it our all with full-force announcements!
こんどはコーナーを用意しました！
We've prepared a new corner!
題して、全力告知、ねぽらは全身アピールー！
Entitled: Full-Force Announcement: Neporabo's Full-Body Appeal!
ちょけんでいいか？ちょけんでいいか？はい、ということで、
Is joking around fine? Is joking okay? Alright, with that said...
こちらはライブリムクで元気が始まって
This is for the live, where energy is starting up—
いらっしゃるねぽらのために… いや、こっちですね。
for Neporabo fans who are getting pumped up— Oh, it's this way.
1人10秒でライブのアピールを全身全力でやってもらいます！
Each person gets 10 seconds to make their live appeal with all their heart!
はい、じゃあ、トップバッターの人、どうぞ。
Alright, then, first batter, please go ahead.
カウント出るから、10秒以内にアピール頑張ってください！
A countdown will show up, so do your best within 10 seconds!
それでは、どうぞ！
Alright, go!
え、なんと今回のライブのために
Um, amazingly, for this live,
書き下ろされた！え、浴衣が心配...
a newly written... Wait, my yukata is worrying me...
浴衣が心配ダンスに映らないようにしてくれてる！あるかもしれない！
My yukata dancing won't show! There might be one!
タイムアップ！おー！すばらしい！タイムキーパー完璧ですね。
Time's up! Whoa! Wonderful! The timekeeper is perfection.
みな伝わった？今の下手くそめせんやね。みんな伝わったかな、これ。
Did it get across to everyone? That was a clumsy gaze. Did everyone get that?
伝わったと、なんか動く、ねぽらの、でもそういうコーナーでしょ？
It got across? Some moving Neporabo... But isn't that the kind of corner it is?
ねぽらぼ新曲あるのかな？あるかもしれない。あるかもしれないから。
Neporabo new song, I wonder? There might be one. There might be one.
え、待って待って、なんでそんな1人の空間みたいなにするの？
Eh, wait, wait, why are you making it feel like it's just your own personal space?
次誰？次誰？次、元気出していこう。
Who's next? Who's next? Next, let's bring up the energy.
はーい、元気のスイッチでね。
Ha-ii, with the energy switch.
ポルカがいきます！誰か言って。
Polka is going! Someone say it.
せーの、かん…
Ready, set, can...
今回のライブのためだけの新しい衣装が見れるかも！このライブのためだけに、
You might get to see brand new outfits just for this live! Since it's only for this live,
絶対見てほしいです！タイムアップ！
you definitely have to check it out! Time's up!
やった！やった！タイムキーパー完璧ですね。
Yay! Yay! The timekeeper is perfection.
よかった！いや素晴らしいビブラートでございました。ということで、
Good job! What wonderful vibrato. With that said,
あ、新しい衣装がみれるかも！あのライブの時は見えるかも！めちゃくちゃ楽しみにしててね！
Ah, you might see new outfits! You might see them at the live! Look forward to it so much!
あ、さっきの、あれ？それはわからな…やだな、このポルカ。
Ah, earlier, huh? I don't get that... How annoying, this Polka.
じゃ、次はー、はい。獅白いきましょう！
Well, next— yes. Shishiro, let's go!
今回のライブは私たちと一緒に盛り上がる！楽しめるライブになります。
This live will be one where we get hyped up and enjoy ourselves together!
タイムアップ！ナイス！ナイス！
Time's up! Nice! Nice!
ラミィ、お前たち、待て、待て三人！最近ちょっと腹筋とか頑張ってるから。
Lamy, you guys, wait, wait, you three! Lately, I've been working hard on my abs.
じゃ、ラミィ頑張れ！みんなの後ろでおねがいします！ゴー！
Alright, Lamy, do your best! Please do it behind everyone! Go!
ライブ会場の東京ドームシティに、ねぽらぼ4人のメッセージを何かに書いてくださいます！
At the live venue, Tokyo Dome City, our four Neporabo messages will be written on something!
タイムアップ！1秒ぐらいかな。うるさいな！
Time's up! About 1 second. So noisy!
みんなわかった？ねぇ、今の聞いてる人分かった？分かった？
Did everyone understand? Hey, did the people listening just now understand? Did you?
なんて言った？「かわいい」っていったの。かわいい？
What did she say? She said "cute". Cute?
ということでね、えっと、まあ、なんとなく分かったかな、みんな？
So with that, um, well, did everyone get the gist of it?
ということでね、みんなに楽しんでもらえる楽しいライブになるので、楽しみに待ててよね！
And so, since it's going to be a fun live that everyone can enjoy, please look forward to it!
あの、もうね、終わりなんですけど、もう終わりなんだけど、なんか後半、今その気になってる
Um, it's already ending, but lately, in the second half, I'm getting into the mood—
踊れるとこ見せとこうかなと。じゃあ、ねねさん、そのまま今日の感想お願いします！
to show where we can dance. Well, Nene-san, please give your thoughts on today!
はい、すごい楽しかったので本番に向けて、ちょっと、みんな開けて見ちゃって、本番に向けて頑張っていきたいと！
Yes, it was super fun, so toward the actual show, everyone take a look, and we want to do our best!
時間ないんで次の方どうぞ！楽しみにしててください！楽しみにしてまーす！
No time, next person please! Please look forward to it! Looking forward to it!
ボタンさんお願いします！
じゃあね、ちょっとね、もうねぽらぼ念願のライブということなので、楽しんでいただきたいです。
Botan-san, please!
Well, you know, since it's Neporabo's long-awaited live, we want you to enjoy it.
楽しみ！
So excited!
はい。
Yeah.
ってことでね、まあ、まだまだこれからも色々あると思いますけれども
So anyway, I'm sure there's still a lot more to come, but
はい！
Yeah!
まずはね、7月7日！
first off, July 7th!
ねぽらぼ、皆様に会うことを楽しみにがんばりますので、皆様よろしくお願いします！
Neporabo is so looking forward to meeting everyone, so we'll do our best!
お願いします！
Please support us!
そして最後は、それぞれのバイバイをしていきます。
And finally, we'll each say our goodbyes.
はい、じゃあ、せーの！
Okay, ready, set!
バイバイねぽらぼー！
Bye-bye, Neporabo!
バイバイねぽらぼ！
あしたもねぽらぼ！
Neporabo tomorrow too!
バイバイねぽらぼー！
Bye-bye, Neporabo!
七夕の奇跡の様に 5期生とみんなが集う場所。
Like a Tanabata miracle, a place where 5th Gen and everyone gather.
それぞれの夢と願いがひとつになった瞬間、
The moment our individual dreams and wishes become one,
新しい輝きが生まれる。
a new radiance is born.
一生の思い出となる
Presenting an irreplaceable night
かけがえの無い一夜をプレゼント。
that will become a lifelong memory.